片名：侏罗纪公园
注意你们头顶!
Everybody, heads up!
别挡着路
Keep it clear.
好  放低点
Okay, down.
别停下来!
Keep going. Come on!
很好  稳住
That's good. Stay.
慢慢降下来
Slow it down.
“努布拉岛”
“哥斯大黎加以西120英里”
推柜组，上去！
Okay, pushing team, move in there. Move it!
预备，电枪手，待命！ 开最强的电击
I want tasers on full charge.
预备，推！
- Steady!
稳住，快，回去！
- Come on, step back in.
好了  动手
All right, move it.
推呀！
And push!
好，让开！
We're unlocked.
装卸组，让开！
Loading team, step away.
开栅的？
Gate keeper.
乔福瑞，开栅！
Jophery, raise the gate.
封住口子，别让她跑出来
Block the opening! Don't let her get out!
来人啊，援救他！逼她退后！
Work her back!
射击她！
Shoot her!
“多明尼加共和国”
“戴奥斯琥珀矿坑”
你好，万尼多！
你好，边尼多
听说老哈没有来 怎么搞的？
What's this I hear at the airport? Hammond's not even here?
他托我向你道歉
He sends his apologies.
工人家属告状 索赔二千万元
We are facing a $20 million lawsuit by the family of that worker...
他连见我一面也嫌麻烦吗
and you're telling me that Hammond can't even be bothered to see me?
他必须提早动身 去安慰他那办离婚的女儿
He had to leave early. He wants to be with his daughter.
这个我谅解 但是我们被通知马上要处理
- She's getting a divorce. - I understand that... but we've been advised to deal with the situation now.
保险公司K
- The insurance company-- - Okay?
保险业者认为这件意外
Underwriters feel the accident's
凸显公园的安全大有问题
raised serious safety questions about the park.
这使得投资人非常地焦虑
That makes the investors very, very anxious.
我不得已答应 要彻底检查场地
I had to promise to conduct a very thorough on-site inspection.
哈蒙最恨检查
Hammond hates inspections.
那会延缓一切进度
They slow everything down.
万尼多，他们会抽走资金 那会使他进行得更慢
Juanito, they'll pull the funding. That'll slow him down even more.
当心头！
Watch your head.
如果有两位专家背书
If two experts sign off on the island...
保险公司就会休兵
the insurance guys will back off.
我找了一位伊恩马康姆 但是他们认为他太时髦
I've already got Ian Malcolm, but they think he's too trendy.
他们要亚伦葛兰
- They want Alan Grant. - Grant?
葛兰？ 你休想叫他离开蒙大拿
- You'll never get him out of Montana.
为什么不行？
- Why not?
（西班牙语）
为什么？
Why not?
因为葛兰像我一样 是挖掘狂
Because Grant's like me. He's a digger.
“巴德兰斯”
“靠近蒙大拿州蛇河”
葛兰博士！塞特勒博士！ 我们准备好再试一次
Dr. Grant, Dr. Sattler, we're ready to try again.
我恨电脑
I hate computers.
我有同感！
The feeling's mutual.
通常这要多久？
- How long does this usually take?
应该是立刻回应
- It should bring an immediate return.
你把雷达波射入地下 骨头的影像弹回来
Shoot the radar into the ground and the bone bounces the image back.
弹回来K
Bounces it back.
这个新软体真是不可思议！
This new program's incredible.
再进步下去 过两年我们就不必挖掘了
A few more years' development and we won't even have to dig anymore.
那还有什么乐趣？
Where's the fun in that?
看来有点变形 但是不是电脑有问题
It's a little distorted, but I don't think it's the computer.
后颈韧带
Postmortem contraction of the posterior neck ligaments.
迅猛龙？
- Velociraptor?
对，形状也很好
- Yes. Good shape too.
有五，六英尺高 我猜它有九英尺长
It's five, six feet high. I'm guessing nine feet long.
-瞧那强壮的K -你做了什么？
- Look at the extraordinary-- - What did you do?
他摸过它 葛兰博士和机器不相容
He touched it. Dr. Grant's not machine compatible.
才怪，他们把我容进去了
They've got it in for me.
瞧那腕部的半月形骨 难怪这些家伙学会了飞行
And look at the half-moon-shaped bones in the wrists. It's no wonder these guys learned how to fly.
说真的！
Seriously.
也许恐龙 和今天的鸟类相同处
Well, maybe dinosaurs have more in common with present-day birds...
多于和爬虫类相同
than they do with reptiles.
看那耻骨 向后转就像鸟类
Look at the pubic bone-- turned backward,just like a bird.
看那脊椎骨节
Look at the vertebrae, full of air sacs and hollows...
布满气囊和空凹 像鸟一样
just like a bird.
甚至“猛禽” 也是指猎食之鸟
And even the word ''raptor'' means ''bird of prey.''
看来并不很吓人
That doesn't look very scary.
更像是一只六英尺高的火鸡
The kid's a pistol. More like a six-foot turkey.
火鸡？
A turkey, huh?
才不是
Oh, no.
好了，试想自己K处在白垩纪
- Okay. - Here we go. Try to imagine yourself in the Cretaceous period.
当你走到开阔地 第一次见到这六英尺高的火鸡
You get your first look at this six-foot turkey as you enter a clearing.
他的行动像鸟 微微地点着头
He moves like a bird... lightly bobbing his head.
你静止不动 你以为他看动的东西时眼才利
And you keep still because you think that maybe his visual acuity... is based on movement, like T-rex, and he'll lose you if you don't move.
但是错了！ 迅猛龙不是这样
But no, not velociraptor.
你瞪着他，他会回瞪你
You stare at him... and he just stares right back.
那正是他攻击的时候
And that's when the attack comes--
不是由正面 是由侧面攻击
not from the front, but from the side...
是另外两只攻击 你根本不知他们来自何方
from the other two raptors... you didn't even know were there.
因为迅猛龙是群攻猎者
Because velociraptor's a pack hunter, you see.
他采用联合攻击
He uses coordinated attack patterns...
今天他们大举出动
and he is out in force today.
他向你挥舞那六寸长
And he slashes at you with this--
伸缩自如的中趾利爪
a six-inch retractable claw-- like a razor-- on the middle toe.
他不像狮子费事的 咬住你喉部
He doesn't bother to bite your jugular, like a lion, say. No, no.
他不来这套 他在你身上乱抓
He slashes at you... here or here.
亚伦！
Oh, Alan.
也许横划开肚子 肚破肠流
Or maybe across the belly... spilling your intestines.
就是说他们吃你时 你还活着
The point is... you are alive when they start to eat you.
所以你们要有点敬畏之心
So, you know... try to show a little respect.
好的！
Okay.
亚伦，你若是要吓孩子们 干脆拔枪对着他
Hey, Alan, if you wanted to scare the kid... you could have pulled a gun on him, you know.
是呀，我知道 可是小孩子K
Yeah, I know. Kids.
你想要这种小孩吗？
You want to have one of those?
我不要那个小孩
I don't want that kid...
那只不过是一个品种
but a breed of child,
葛兰博士，可能很有趣！
Dr. Grant, could be intriguing.
我是说，小孩有什么不好
- I mean, what's so wrong with kids?
爱莉，听着，小孩们吵闹
- Oh, Ellie, look. They're noisy,
脏乱而且很花钱
they're messy, they're expensive.
养小孩便宜，便宜
Cheap, cheap.
小孩都有体臭
- They smell.
他们不臭
- They do not smell.
-有些小孩臭 -你饶了我吧！
- Some of them smell. - Give me a break.
婴儿有体臭
Babies smell.
-把它掩盖起来 -把现场掩盖起来
- Cover the site! - Cover up the dig!
掩盖坑洞
- Tell them to shut down! - Cut the machine!
掩盖现场
全部盖起来!
Cover it all up!
把它拿走!
Okay, pull it over!
该死，熄火 熄火好吗？
Just cut it, will you? Cut it out! Shut it down!
熄火！什么？
What?
你在搞什么鬼？
What the hell do you think you're doing in here?
那是我们保留的酒
Hey! We were saving that!
为今天保留，我保证
For today. I guarantee it.
你是什么东西？
-Who in God's name do you think you are? -John Hammond.
约翰哈蒙德 很高兴终于见到你，葛博士！
And I'm delighted to meet you finally in person, Dr. Grant.
看来我每年赞助 五万元很值得
- Mr. Hammond-- - I can see that my... fifty thousand dollars a year has been well spent.
好，这个浑蛋是谁？
Okay, who's the jerk?
这是我们的原始植物学家
- This is our paleobotanist,
-塞特勒！ -塞特勒博士
Doctor-- - Sattler.
爱莉，这是哈蒙德先生
Ellie, this is Mr. Hammond.
塞特勒博士 原谅我来得轰动
Sorry about the dramatic entrance, Dr. Sattler...
我骂过“浑蛋”吗？
- Did I say ''jerk''? - but we're in a wee bit of a hurry.
我们有一点匆忙 喝一杯好吗？
Will you have a drink? We won't let it get warm.
不要让酒热了 来吧！坐下！坐下！
Come along. Sit down.
来，这个给我
- Here. Let me--
我只要喝一两杯，那是K 不必，不必！
- We'll just get a glass or two.No, no, no.
我可以自己来
I can manage this.
厨房的事我很熟
I know my way around a kitchen.
现在我要开门见山的说
Now, I'll get right to the point.
我喜欢你们两个
I like you-- both of you.
我一眼就能识人 这是我的天赋
I can tell instantly about people. It's a gift.
我在哥斯大黎加外海 拥有海岛
I own an island... off the coast of Costa Rica.
我向政府租的
I've leased it from the government,
五年来在岛上 建立生物保存
and I've spent the last five years...setting up a kind of biological preserve.
真的可观，不惜工本
Really spectacular. Spared no expense.
我在肯亚的保育区 相形之下像个宠物园
Make the one I've got down in Kenya look like a petting zoo.
我们的吸引力 准会使儿童发狂
And there's no doubt our attractions will drive kids out of their minds.
什么“吸引力”？
And what are those?
就是吸引力嘛！亲爱的！
Small versions of adults, honey.
不只是小孩，是每一个人
And not just kids, everyone.
如果律师没搞垮我 明年就可以开张！
We're going to open next year-- that is, if the lawyers don't kill me first.
我不怕律师，你呢？
I don't care for lawyers. Do you?
我们不认识什么律师
- We don't really know any. - We don't know any.
恐怕我认识
Well, I do, I'm afraid.
目前我那些投资人 正找我麻烦
There's a particular pebble in my shoe represents my investors.
他们一定要客观的意见
Says that they insist on outside opinions.
什么样的意见？
What kind of opinions?
你们的意见 不必评得太好
Your kind, not to put too fine a point on it.
老实说吧！ 你们在本行中是佼佼者
In your particular field, you're the top minds...
如果我能说动你们 批准这公园
and if I could just persuade you to sign off on the park--
就是得到你们背书
you know, give it your endorsement, maybe
即使是一句证言 我就可以恢复计划 计划！
even pen a wee testimonial--I could get back on schedule.
他们何必在乎我们的想法
- Why would they care what we think?
这是什么样的公园？
- What kind of park is this?
这正是你的本行
It's right up your alley.
我告诉你们 你们何不结伴去那边度个周末
I'll tell you what. Why don't you come down-- just the pair of you-- for the weekend.
我也很乐意 听原始植物学家的意见
I'd love to have an opinion of a paleobotanist as well.
我的喷射机正在巧朵待命
I've got a jet standing by at Choteau.
这K很抱歉，这是不可能的
I'm sorry. This is impossible.
-是啊，我们K -我们今天刚挖起一具新骨骸
We just dug up a new skeleton.
我可以K全额赞助 你们的挖掘
I could compensate you by fully funding your dig.
-这是非常时期 -时机上K
And this is a very unusual time.
再赞助三年
For a further three years.
好吧
Well--
飞机在那里？
Where's the plane?
是呀，好！
- Yeah. Okay. - Cheers.
-三年！ -干杯！
- Three years. - Cheers.
好呀！
Okay.
“哥斯大黎加，圣荷西市”
陶吉森
Yo! Dodgson!
你不该用我的姓名
You shouldn't use my name.
陶吉森！陶吉森在此
We've got Dodgson here!
你看，没有人在乎
See? Nobody cares.
帽子不错！
Nice hat.
你想打扮得像情报员吗？
What are you trying to look like, a secret agent?
七十五万元 每交一个胚胎加付五万
- Well? - Seven fifty. On delivery, 50,000 more for each viable embryo.
如果你把十五个物种都弄到 就有一百五十万元进帐
That's 1 .5 million, if you get all 1 5 species off the island.
我会全部弄到手
- Oh, I'll get them all. - Remember-- viable embryos.
记住要活胚胎 若不是活的就没有用
They're no use to us if they don't survive.
我怎么运送他们？
How am I supposed to transport them?
底层可以转开
The bottom screws open.
那太好了，我的天！
That's great. Oh, God.
里面有夹层又凉
It's cooled and compartmentalized inside.
你们真厉害！
You guys-- Oh, that's great.
甚至于可以任由海关检查
Customs can even check it if they want to.
-来，让我看看！ -看吧！
- Let me see. - Go on.
里面的冷却剂可维持36小时
- Enough coolant inside for 36 hours.
不是薄荷脑吗？
- No menthol?
胚胎必须在这段时间 运到圣荷西
The embryos have to be back here in San Jose by then.
那要看你们船上的人了
That's up to your guy on the boat.
明晚七点钟在东码头 要确保他会到
7:00 tomorrow night on the east dock. Make sure he gets it right.
你打算如何通过安全检查
How are you planning to beat security?
我开个十八分钟的天窗
I've got an 1 8-minute window.
十八分钟 使你公司的研发进步了十年
Eighteen minutes and your company catches up on ten years of research.
陶吉森，不要太小气
Don't get cheap on me, Dodgson.
这要怪哈蒙德
That was Hammond's mistake.
你们是K挖掘恐龙的？
So you two dig up dinosaurs?
这个K
Well--
我们是想挖到
We try to.
你必须适应马康姆博士
You'll have to get used to Dr. Malcolm.
他患了数学家特有的任性症
He suffers from a deplorable excess of personality... especially for a mathematician.
其实是混乱方程式
Chaotician, actually. John doesn't subscribe to chaos...
约翰不赞成混乱 尤其是说到他那科学小计划
particularly what it has to say about his science project.
伊恩！胡说！ 你从未有效地说明岛上的事
Codswallop, Ian. You've never been able to sufficiently explain your concerns about the island.
约翰啊，约翰！约翰！ 因为这行为系统是假想的
Because of the behavior of the system in phase space?
只是一叠时髦的数字统计
A load, if I may say so, of fashionable number crunching.
拜托，别捏我的膝盖！
- Is not. - I do wish you wouldn't do that.
塞博士！葛博士！ 你们听说过混乱原理吗？
Dr. Sattler, Dr. Grant, you've heard of chaos theory?
不！
No
不？不是一次方程式吗？
No? Nonlinear equations?
奇怪的吸引力
Strange attractors?
塞博士！我不相信 你对引力原理没概念
Dr. Sattler, I refuse to believe... that you aren't familiar with the concept of attraction.
我带科学家来 你带摇滚明星来
I bring scientists, you bring a rock star.
到了！
There it is.
风势恶劣 我们必须急遽下坠
Bad wind shears. We have to drop pretty fast, so hold on...
所以要抓紧 这可能会颠簸
'cause it can be just a little thrilling.
不对！要用那个环扣这个
You need that piece over there, and that piece--
等你扣好已经着陆了，来吧！
We'll have landed by the time you get it right. Come along.
好方法！
Good idea.
“侏罗纪公园”
“危险，电压一万伏特”
长五十英里的周边网墙 筑好没？
The full 50 miles of perimeter fence are in place?
还有水泥护沟 行动侦测系统都好了，唐纳老弟
And the concrete moats, and the motion-sensor tracking systems.
放心吧！尽量的享受！
Donald, dear boy, relax. Try and enjoy yourself.
约翰，坦白说 这可不是周末游览
Let's get something straight,John. This is not a weekend excursion.
而是要严查此岛上的安全性
This is a serious investigation of the stability of the island.
我代表你的投资人 非常关切
Your investors, whom I represent, are deeply concerned.
四十八小时内 如果他们和我未被说服
Forty-eight hours from now, if they're not convinced, I'm not convinced.
我会叫你关门，约翰！
I'll shut you down,John.
四十八小时内 你会向我赔罪
In 48 hours, I'll be accepting your apologies.
在这里减速，慢！慢！
All right, slow down here.
停！停！停！
Stop, stop, stop.
这不应该在这里！
This shouldn't be here.
亚伦，这类物种白垩纪时已灭绝
Alan, this species of veriforman's been extinct... since the Cretaceous period.
我是说这东西是K 这东西K
This thing is extinct.
什么？什么？
What?
看
Look at that.
这是一只恐龙
It's-- It's a dinosaur.
你做到了！ 你这个疯狂的龟儿子做到了
You did it. You crazy son of a bitch, you did.
爱莉，可以撕掉 冷血动物法则了
We could just tear up the rule book on coldbloodedness.
这法则完全错了 这是“热血生物”
It doesn't apply. They're totally wrong. - This is a warm-blooded creature.
这东西不是活在
- This thing doesn't live in a swamp.
它的脖子有25？ 27英尺长？
This thing's got what, a 25, 27-foot neck?
腕龙？30英尺
- Brachiosaur? Thirty.
三十英尺！
- Thirty feet.
这地方会让我们大发财
We're gonna make a fortune with this place.
它们能跑多快？
How fast are they?
暴龙能跑时速32英里
We clocked the T-rex at 3 2 miles an hour.
霸王龙属的暴龙？
T-rex?
你们有暴龙？
- You said you've got a T-rex? - Uh-huh.
再说一遍！
Say again?
我们有暴龙
We have a T-rex.
头低下免得昏倒！
Put your head between your knees.
葛博士！亲爱的塞博士
Dr. Grant, my dear Dr. Sattler...
欢迎光临侏罗纪公园
welcome... toJurassic Park.
你看他们成群结队的活动！
They're moving in herds.
真的成群！
They do move in herds.
你怎么做的？
How'd you do this?
我会给你看！
I'll show you.
大家好！大家好！ 亲爱的！
G'day, g'day, g'day!
世界上最先进的游乐园
Now, the most advanced... amusement park in the entire world...
集尖端科技之大成
incorporating all the latest technologies.
不是指云霄飞车 那个到处都有
And I'm not talking just about rides. Everybody has rides.
我们创造了生物吸引力
We have made living biological attractions so astounding...
惊世骇俗 将抓住全球的想像
that they'll capture the imagination of the entire planet.
你在想什么？
So what are you thinking?
想到我们失业了
We're out of a job.
你是说要绝种了吗？
Don't you mean ''extinct''?
大家坐下好吗？
Well, why don't you all sit down there?
唐纳，坐下！坐下！
Donald, sit down.
来了，他来了！
Ah. Here he comes-- Oh--
我来了！
here I come.
你好！
Hello. Hello.
问好呀！问好！
Say hello.
你好！
hello.
你K你好！
好，约翰！
Hello,John.
对了，我有台词
Oh, yes. I've got lines.
好！好！我还好
Well, fine, I guess.
我是怎么来的？
But how did I get here?
我给你们看
Let me show you.
首先我需要一滴血 你的血
First, I'll need a drop of blood--your blood.
对
Right
约翰，那样会痛
John, that hurt.
别紧张 这是同体生物的奇迹
Relax,John. It's all part of the miracle of cloning.
好，约翰
- Hello,John.
好，约翰，你好
与什么同体？
Cloned from what?
基因不能再造完整的DNA索
Blood extraction has never recreated an intact DNA strand.
有太多断层
Not without massive sequence gaps.
原始去氧核糖核酸 从何取得？
Paleo DNA-- from what source?
上哪找一亿年前的恐龙血
Where do you get 1 00-million-year-old dinosaur blood?
什么？什么？
What? What?
DNA先生 你是从哪来的？
Mr. DNA. Where did you come from?
从你的血来的
From your blood.
你一滴血 就有几十亿DNA索
Just one drop of your blood contains billions of strands of DNA...
都是建造生命的“砖块”
the building blocks of life.
像我这种DNA索 是建造生命的蓝图
A DNA strand like me is a blueprint for building a living thing...
有时候 灭绝了几百万年的动物
and sometimes, animals that went extinct millions of years ago--
例如恐龙
like dinosaurs--
留下蓝图让我们去找
left their blueprints behind for us to find.
我们只要会找
We just had to know where to look.
一亿年前的蚊子 就像今天的蚊子
A hundred million years ago... there were mosquitoes, just like today.
像今天一样吸动物的血
And,just like today, they fed on the blood of animals,
甚至吸恐龙的血
even dinosaurs.
有时候吸恐龙血之后
Sometimes, after biting a dinosaur...
蚊子会停在树枝上 被树液包住
the mosquito would land on the branch of a tree... and get stuck in the sap.
时间一久 树液硬化成了化石
After a long time, the tree sap would get hard...
就像恐龙的骨骸
and become fossilized, just like a dinosaur bone...
树液保存了蚊子
preserving the mosquito inside.
树液化石又称为琥珀
This fossilized tree sap... which we call "amber"...
包住蚊子等了几百万年
waited for millions of years with the mosquito inside...
等到侏罗纪公园的 科学家前来
until Jurassic Park scientists came along.
他们用高科技 抽取蚊子吸的血
Using sophisticated techniques... they extract the preserved blood from the mosquito...
中奖一样获得恐龙DNA
and bingo-- dino DNA.
完整的DNA索 有三十亿遗传密码
A full DNA strand contains three billion genetic codes.
这样一秒钟看一种 一天看八小时
If we looked at screens like these once a second for eight hours a day...
看完DNA索也要两年
it'd take two years to look at the entire DNA strand--
那么长的DNA索
It's that long.
由于它很老所以尽是漏洞
Since it's so old, it's full of holes.
这就要我们的 遗传学家接手了
Now, that's where our geneticists take over.
思想的机器“超级电脑”
Thinking-machine super computers and gene sequencers...
基因顺序在几分钟内破解
break down the strand in minutes...
现出了DNA序中的断层
and virtual-reality displays show our geneticists... the gaps in the DNA sequence.
我们用青蛙的DNA序 来补漏洞
We use the complete DNA of a frog to fill in the holes...
拼出完整的密码
and complete the code.
现在我们能造恐龙宝宝了
And now we can make a baby dinosaur.
这段过程当然要配乐了
This score is only temporary. It all has very dramatic music, of course.
激昂的进行曲 曲子还没作好
A march or something. It hasn't been written yet.
当然要继续参观
And then, of course, the tour moves on.
看看这个
Well, look here.
辛勤工作的科学家K
These hard-working cowpokes you see behind the glass--
约翰，真是帅呆了
This is overwhelming,John.
这些人物是机器卡通吗？
Are these characters autoerotica?
不是，这里没有机器人
No, no, no. We have no animatronics here.
那些是创造 侏罗纪公园奇迹的人
Those people are the real miracle workers ofJurassic Park.
未受精的鸸鹋或鸵鸟蛋
The unfertilized emu or ostrich eggs.
等一下 怎样阻断细胞间接分裂？
- Then it's no-- - Wait a minute. How do you interrupt the cellular mitosis?
可否看看未受精的卵？
- Can't we see the unfertilized eggs?
快了！快了！
- Shortly.- Shortly.
现在一整队的遗传工程师
Now a whole team of genetic engineers--
这可以停止吗？
- Can't you stop these things?
对不起，这有点像游览
- I'm sorry. It's a kind of a ride.
我们离开这里 一、二、三！
One, two, three.
你不能这样做
Can't do that.
什么？
Why?
他们可以那样做吗？
Can they do that?
注意，往内陆的船七点开
A reminder-- The boat for the mainland will be leaving at 1 900 hours.
全体员工于6点45分前 到码头
All personnel be at the dock no later than 1 845.
不得有误！
No exceptions.
好，亨利
G'day, Henry.
你好，老板
Oh, good day, sir.
它在转动蛋！
It's turning the eggs.
天啊，你看 正好赶上
Oh, perfect timing.
希望我上船之前蛋都孵化
I'd hoped they'd hatch before I had to go to the boat.
亨利！怎么不早说？
Henry, why didn't you tell me?
我一定要在此看他们出世
I insist... on being here when they're born.
加油！加油！
Come on.
小家伙！加油！
Come on, little one.
加油！快加油呀！
Come on, Come on,
很好，推呀！
Come on, then.
非常好！
Very good. Push!
-非常好！ -我的天！
- Very good. - Oh, God.
推呀！加油！
Come on,
快加油！
你出来了！出来了！
There you are. There you are.
她们对最先接触的人 印象最深
They imprint on the first creature they come in contact with.
对，帮助她们来信任我
That's it! Helps them to trust me.
岛上的小东西 出世我都在场
I've been present for the birth... of every little creature on this island.
当然，在野地出生的不算
Well, surely not the ones that have bred in the wilds.
其实她们不能在野地繁殖
- Yes. - Actually they can't breed in the wild.
数量控制是本园的安全项目
Population control is one of our security precautions.
侏罗纪公园不准私生恐龙
There's no unauthorized breeding in Jurassic Park.
你怎么知道她们不能繁殖
How do you know they can't breed?
因为园里的动物都是母的
Because all the animals in Jurassic Park are female.
我们精心设计的
- Oh. - We've engineered them that way.
你出来了
There you are.
天啊，你们看
Oh, God! Look at that.
血温似乎有华氏80多度
Blood temperature seems like a high 80s maybe.
小吴？
- Wu? -
91度！
Ninety-one.
是恒温动物？ 它能保持这温度？
Homeothermic? - It holds that temperature? - Yeah.
不可思议
That's incredible.
怎么？再请问你 怎么知道都是母的？
But again, how do you know they're all female?
有人到园里 掀恐龙的裙子看吗？
Does somebody go out in the park... and pull up the dinosaurs' skirts?
我们控制她们的染色体 其实这也不难
We control their chromosomes. It's really not that difficult.
所有的脊椎胚胎 天生是母的
All vertebrate embryos are inherently female anyway.
只需要在发展时期 适时加所需的荷尔蒙就变公的
They require an extra hormone given... at the right developmental stage to make them male.
我们就是不给她们
- We simply deny them that.
不给她们？
- Deny them that?
约翰，你尝试要控制的事 是不可能的
John, the kind of control you're attempting is-- It's not possible.
进化史如果有教我们什么
If there's one thing the history of evolution has taught us...
那就是“生命不受抑制”
it's that life will not be contained.
“生命是奔放的”
Life breaks free.
生命开拓新的领域，冲破障碍
It expands to new territories and crashes...
有痛苦甚至危险
through barriers painfully, maybe even dangerously, but--
但是生命如此
Well, there it is.
生命在此！
There it is.
你是说全是母的也会繁殖
You're implying that a group composed entirely of female animals will breed?
不是 我只是说生命会找出路
No. I'm simply saying... that life finds a way.
这是什么物种？
What species is this?
这是迅猛龙
It's a velociraptor.
你繁殖猛禽？
You bred raptors?
葛博士，我刚才正说到K
Dr. Grant, as I was saying...
你入园之前，我们已备好午餐
we laid on lunch for you before you set out into the park.
-我们的美食大师傅K -他们在做什么？
- Our gourmet chef, Alejandro-- - What are they doing?
喂她们吃
Feeding them.
亚历山卓准备了好菜 智利海鲈
Alejandro has prepared a delightful menu for us. Chilean sea bass, I believe.
请？
Shall we?
应该把她们全部消减
They should all be destroyed.
劳勃马杜尔 我从肯亚调来的
Robert Muldoon, my game warden from Kenya.
紧张多虑但是最了解猛禽
Bit of an alarmist, I'm afraid, but knows more about raptors than anyone.
他们的新陈代谢成长率如何？ 生长率又怎样？
What kind of metabolism do they have? What's their growth rate?
她们八个月大就能杀生 我是说真的致命
They're lethal at eight months-- and I do mean lethal.
我猎杀过许多会猎杀的东西 但她们的速度K
I've hunted most things that can hunt you, but the way these things move--
在两足动物算快吗？
- Fast for a biped?
快如猎豹
- Cheetah speed.
在开阔地能跑五六十英里时速 而且是跳跃高手了
Fifty, sixty miles per hour, if they ever got out in the open. And they're astonishing jumpers.
对！对！ 所以我们非常小心
That's why we're taking extreme precautions.
她们有智慧吗？
- The viewing area set below here-- - Do they show intelligence?
-从她们的脑腔大小假定K -她们表现得很聪明
-With their brain cavities, we assumed-- -They're extremely intelligent...
甚至有排除困难的智慧
even problem-solving intelligence,
尤其是那只大的
especially the big one.
我们原本繁殖八只
We bred eight originally, but when she came in...
但是她一来就扬威 杀得只剩下两只
she took over the pride and killed all but two of the others. That one...
那一只在看你的时候 在用心机
when she looks at you, you can see she's working things out.
所以我们要这样喂她们
That's why we have to feed them like this.
喂食的时候 她令其他的撞网墙
She had them all attacking the fences when the feeders came.
网墙通了电是吗？
The fences are electrified though, right?
不错 但她们从来不撞同一处
That's right, but they never attacked the same place twice.
她们有系统地 找网墙的弱点
They were testing the fences for weaknesses systematically.
她们记得
They remember.
是呀！
Yes, well.
谁饿了？
Who's hungry?
敢冒险的游客 可以走丛林水路
More adventurous guests can opt for ourjungle river cruise...
近观有翼的恐龙K
or for a close-up look at our majestic winged dinosaurs--
当然这些项目都没有完工
None of these attractions are ready yet...
但是先开放你们下面的游程
but the park will open with the basic tour you're about to take...
其他游程在6或12个月后开放
and then other rides will come on-line six or twelve months after that.
绝对令人叹为观止 不惜工本
Absolutely spectacular designs. Spared no expense.
我们可以狮子大开口 一天的费用两千，一万
And we can charge anything we want-- 2,000 a day, 1 0,000 a day--
人们都愿意付
and people will pay it.
还卖商品，我建议K
And then there's the merchandise. I can personally--
唐纳！唐纳！
Donald,Donald,
这公园 不是只迎合超级富翁的
This park was not built to cater only for the super rich.
世上人人都有权 欣赏这些动物
Everyone in the world has the right to enjoy these animals.
当然，他们会看到 我们会订出优待的日子
Sure. They will. What, we'll have a coupon day or something.
对大自然缺乏谦卑 叫人怕怕！
Gee, the lack of humility before nature... that's being displayed here staggers me.
马博士，谢谢你 但是这跟你我所怕的不同
Thank you, Dr. Malcolm, but I think things are a little bit different...
我知道，更可怕
- than you and I had feared. - Yeah, I know. They're a lot worse.
我们还没参观园区K
Now, wait a second. We haven't even seen the park yet.
不要紧，唐纳，让他说
- I mean-- - No, Donald, let him talk.
我要听各方意见，真的！
There's no reason. I want to hear every viewpoint.
你没看见这样做的危险吗
- I really do. - Don't you see the danger... John, inherent in what you're doing here?
遗传是地球上最可怕的力量
Genetic power's the most awesome force the planet's ever seen...
你等于是小孩偷玩大人的枪
but you wield it like a kid that's found his dad's gun.
事前谈危险不恰当K
- It's hardly appropriate to start-- -Just a second.
容我说句话
If I may.
你在此用的科学力量问题 在于它没有任何约束
I'll tell you the problem with the scientific power you're using here. It didn't require any discipline to attain it.
你读别人的研究 然后采取行动
You read what others had done and you took the next step.
你的知识不是自己的 所以你不负任何责任
You didn't earn the knowledge for yourselves... so you don't take any responsibility for it.
你站在天才们的肩膀上K
You stood on the shoulders of geniuses...
尽快地去做成一些事K
to accomplish something as fast as you could...
还没弄清楚已申请到专利 然后包装，现在快要销售了
and before you even knew what you had... you patented it, and packaged it... and slapped it on a plastic lunch box.
你想要出售它
And now you're selling it. You want to sell it. Well--
你对我们的批评有失公道
I don't think you're giving us our due credit.
我们的科学家们 成就了前无古人的创举
Our scientists have done things which nobody's ever done before.
但是你的专家只知埋头硬干
But your scientists were so preoccupied with whether or not they could...
没思考该不该做
they didn't stop to think if they should.
兀鹰，兀鹰正濒临绝种
Condors. Condors are on the verge of extinction.
如果我K不！不！ 如果我在岛上造一群秃鹰
If I was to create a flock of condors on this island...
-你就没话说了！ -不，等一下！
-you wouldn't have anything to say. - Hold on.
这个物种并非因为砍伐森林K
This isn't some species that was obliterated by deforestation...
或是建水坝而绝种的
or the building of a dam.
恐龙K曾经有机会生存
Dinosaurs had their shot...
是大自然要他们灭绝
and nature selected them for extinction.
竟然有人因噎废食 尤其还是个科学家
I simply don't understand this Luddite attitude... especially from a scientist.
我们在发明的光照耀下 怎能不行动？
How can we stand in the light of discovery and not act?
发明有什么好？那是暴力
What's so great about discovery?
它是狂暴刺穿的行为 到处留疤痕
It's a violent, penetrative act that scars what it explores.
你所谓的发明
What you call discovery...
我叫它做“强奸自然界”
I call the rape of the natural world.
问题是你如何能了解K 一种灭绝的生态系统？
The question is, how can you know anything about an extinct ecosystem?
因此你如何设想 控制的办法？
And therefore, how could you ever assume that you can control it?
你这栋楼里有含毒的植物
You have plants in this building that are poisonous.
你见它好看而摆设
You picked them because they look good...
但是恐龙有侵略性 它不管时代
but these are aggressive living things that have no idea...
必要时它们会用暴力自卫
what century they're in, and they'll defend themselves-- violently, if necessary.
葛博士！如果在座有一个人
Dr. Grant, if there's one person here...
能欣赏我在做的努力K
who could appreciate what I'm trying to do--
世界急遽的改变 我们在迎头赶上
The world has just changed so radically... and we're all running to catch up.
我不想妄下论断
I don't want to jump to any conclusions, but look.
但是恐龙和人类
Dinosaurs and man--
两个物种相差六千五百万年
two species separated by 65 million years of evolution--
忽然间被送做堆了
have just been suddenly thrown back into the mix together.
我们能期望什么呢？
How can we possibly have the slightest idea... of what to expect?
我不敢相信！
I don't believe it.
你们原本是来帮我辩护的
You're meant to come down here and defend me against these characters...
如今只有吸血的律师 帮我说话
and the only one I've got on my side is the bloodsucking lawyer.
谢谢你！
Thank you.
他们来了
they're here.
你们四个将在园里 跟我们安排的观众同游
You four are going to have a spot of company out in the park-- spend a little time with our target audience.
外公！
Grandpa!
孩子们！
Kids!
-慢着，别撞倒我 -我们想念你
- Careful with the old man. - We missed you.
外公，谢谢你的礼物 礼物好棒
- Thanks for the presents. - We loved the presents.
我很高兴 坐直升机好玩吗？
- They were great. - Did you enjoy the helicopter?
-好玩，它下坠我们上升 -爷爷，它呼一声过去K
Yeah, it went down, and we all went right up.
孩子们，来 别太靠近车辆
Now kids, come away. Not too close to the cars.
他们可不可爱？ 讨不讨人喜欢？
Aren't they lovely? Aren't they glorious, though?
这些将是你们下午的交通工具
These will be your transports for the afternoon.
没有司机？
- No drivers?
没有！没有，用不着司机 这是电动的
- Oh, no. No drivers.They're electric.
在路中央的轨道上跑
They run on this track in the middle of the roadway.
完全无污染 最好的路线，不惜工本
Totally non-polluting. Top of the line. Spared no expense.
这是雷射唱片唯读记忆体
It's an interactive CD-ROM.
看见没有？你按右边 它就会讲你要听的事
You just touch the right part of the screen... and it talks about whatever you want.
莉丝，你那里好坐吗？ 塞博士，跟我来
Lex, Darling, you're all right in there.
葛博士，上第二辆车
Dr. Sattler, come with me. Dr. Grant, come in the second car.
我要和塞博士坐一辆
I'm going with Dr. Sattler.
我读过你的书
I read your book.
这K那好呀！
Well, that's-- That's great.
你真的认为恐龙变化成鸟吗？ 他们都是变成鸟吗？
Do you really think dinosaurs turned into birds... and that's where they all went?
有少数物种也许曾经进化
Well, a few species may have evolved along those lines.
我看它们决不像鸟
They sure don't look like birds to me.
我听说有块陨石K
I heard that there was this meteor...
落在墨西哥某处 撞出一个大坑
hit the Earth someplace down in Mexico and made this big crater.
听我说K
Listen--
丁姆！
Tim.
丁姆，你要坐那一辆车？
Tim. Which car were you planning on?
跟你坐同一辆
Whichever one you are.
我在“全知”上读到过
Then I read about this thing in Omni.
这块陨石产生热度
About this meteor making all this heat...
造成一团钻石沙，改变了气候 恐龙死于改变的气候
and it made a bunch of diamond dust. And that changed the weather, and they died because of the weather.
然后我的老师提到 贝克写的书
And then my teacher tells me about this other book...
贝克说K
by a guy named Bakker, and he says--
她说我应该和你坐 对你有好处
She said I should ride with you because it would be good for you.
船正在上客
The boat is now loading.
每个人都要赶七点离开
Everyone must be on the dock for the 1 900 hour departure.
气象局在追踪离我们西方 约75英里的热带暴风
National Weather Service is tracking a tropical storm... about 7 5 miles west of us.
我为什么不在奥兰多建园
Why didn't I build in Orlando?
我会注意，也许又会转向
I'll keep an eye on it. Maybe it'll swing south, like the last one.
雷，展开游览节目
Ray, start the tour program.
坐稳！
Hold on to your butts.
“游览开始”
“游客中心，第一区”
-我们要看那一种恐龙？ -不知道
What kind of dinosaurs are we going to see now?
-可能你不知道她们的名称 -开动了
Hey, look. A ghost.
加入未来的行列
At the door and join the future, right?
上帝救我们！
Oh, God help us. We're in the hands of engineers.
大部份行程中 适当的资讯将会自动为你显示
During most of your tour, the appropriate information... will be automatically selected and displayed for you.
-喂，快看！ -只要触摸荧光幕K
- Hey, look! -Simply touch the area of the screen...
我们会撞上大门吗？
- displaying the appropriate icon. - Are we gonna hit that?
欢迎光临侏罗纪公园
Welcome toJurassic Park.
里面养着什么，大金刚？
What have they got in there, King Kong?
你听到的是客人凯利的声音 我们不惜工本
The voice you're now hearing is Richard Kiley. - We spared no expense. - If you look to the right...
看右边你将看见 第一群恐龙
you will see a herd of the first...
叫作“双脊龙”
dinosaurs on our tour, called dilophosaurus.
双脊龙
- Dilophosaurus!
天啊！
- Oh, shit!
最早的肉食动物之一 其实双脊龙有毒
One of the earliest carnivores... we now know dilophosaurus is actually poisonous...
它向猎物喷毒汁
spitting its venom at its prey, causing...
-造成对方失明和瘫痪 -“注意！窗子上紧”
blindness and eventually paralysis...
任由它大快朵颐
allowing the carnivore to eat at its leisure.
它使本园增添美丽 却又致命的特色
- I can't see. - This makes dilophosaurus... a beautiful but deadly addition... toJurassic Park.
亚伦，双脊龙在哪？
Alan... where--
可恶！
Damn.
车灯亮却没反应 车不会没电
Vehicle headlights are on and they're not responding. Those shouldn't be running off the car batteries.
第151项目今天故障
Item 1 51 on today's glitch list.
游乐园和动物园的毛病都有 而电脑还没建立起来
We have all the problems of a major theme park and a major zoo... and the computers aren't even on their feet yet.
丹尼斯！
Dennis...
人命关天，你还有空吃糖？
our lives are in your hands, and you have butterfingers?
我真是白干了！
I'm totally unappreciated in my time.
你可以用最少的人 控制全园区
You can run this park from this room with minimal staff for up to 3 days.
你以为自动化容易吗？
You think that kind of automation is easy?
便宜吗？
Or cheap?
你认识谁能建立八连机器
You know anybody who can network eight connection machines...
像我这样改正两百万个程式？
and debug two million lines of code for what I bid for this job?
如果有我倒想见识
'Cause if you can, I'd love to see him try.
丹尼斯，你财务困难我很同情
I'm sorry about your financial problems, Dennis, I really am...
但那是你的问题
but they are your problems.
约翰，你没有错 都是我不好
You're right. You're absolutely right. Everything's my problem.
我不要再跟你争论财务问题
I will not get drawn into another financial debate with you, Dennis.
我真的不要！
- I really will not.
根本没有争论过
- There's been hardly any debate at all.
我不怪别人犯错
I don't blame people for their mistakes...
但是我一定 要他们为错付代价
but I do ask that they pay for them.
谢了！岳父！
- Thanks, Dad.
丹尼斯！前灯！
- Dennis, the headlights.
等他们回来后 我改正好吗？
I'll debug the tour program when they get back, okay?
好吗？ 那会吃掉计算环，会暂时失灵
Okay? It'll eat a lot of compute cycles. We'll lose part of the system for a while.
记忆有限，不能做所有的事
There's a finite amount of memory.
要不要半小时？
- You gonna compile for a half an hour?
大家安静！
- Quiet, all of you.
他们快到暴龙园地了
They're approaching the tyrannosaur paddock.
上帝创造恐龙
God creates dinosaurs.
上帝毁灭恐龙
God destroys dinosaurs.
上帝创造人
God creates man.
人毁灭上帝
Man destroys God.
人创造恐龙
Man creates dinosaurs.
恐龙吃男人
Dinosaurs... eat man.
女人继承了地球
Woman inherits the Earth.
我们要尝试食诱暴龙
We'll try to tempt the rex now. Keep watching the fence.
那只羊会怎样？
What's gonna happen to the goat?
它会吃那只羊吗？
He's gonna eat the goat?
好过瘾
Excellent.
孩子，怎么了？
What's the matter, kid?
你没吃过羊肉吗？
You never had lamb chops?
我正好吃素！
I happen to be a vegetarian.
暴龙不要被喂食 他要猎食
T-rex doesn't want to be fed. He wants to hunt.
六千五百万年的天性改不了
Can't just... suppress 65 million years of gut instinct.
你终于在恐龙之旅 安排恐龙了
Now eventually you do plan to have dinosaurs... on your dinosaur tour, right?
“内部监控”
喂？
Hello?
是吗？
Yes?
我真恨那个人
I really hate that man.
暴龙不服从即定模式 不听摆布
See, the tyrannosaur... doesn't obey any set patterns or park schedules.
正是混乱之本
It's the essence of chaos.
我还是不懂混乱原理
I'm still not clear on chaos.
这很简单K 只是处理复杂系统中的不测
It simply deals with... unpredictability in complex systems.
简称为“蝴蝶效应”
The shorthand is the Butterfly Effect.
蝴蝶在北京 你在中央公园淋雨
A butterfly can flap its wings in Peking... and in Central Park you get rain instead of sunshine.
什么？
Why?
-我说得太笼统了？ -太含糊
- Did I go too fast?
我走得太快，我是飞过去
I did a fly-by. - Yes.
拿那杯水给我，实验给你看 我们来做个实验
Give me that glass of water. We're going to conduct an experiment.
应该静止，但车子颠簸
It should be still. The car's bouncing up and down.
不要紧，只是示范
But that's okay. It's just an example.
手做象形文字状
Put your hand flat, like a hieroglyphic.
现在手上落一滴水
Now, let's say a drop of water falls on your hand.
水滴会滚向手背还是拇指
Which way is the drop going to roll off? Which finger?
我不K向拇指
Thumb, I'd say.
好！
Aha. Okay.
好，手静止！静止！
Now freeze your hand. Don't move.
别动！我要同样在同一处滴水 由同一个地方再开始
I'm going to do the same thing, start with the same place again.
它会往那边流？
Which way is it gonna roll off?
向后K跟前次一样
Let's say back. The same way.
同一方向，假定是同样向后
Same way? Back the same way.
它转向了，为什么？
It changed. Why?
因为有微小的变化
Because tiny variations--
汗毛导向改变K
the orientation of the hairs on your hands--
亚伦，你看这个！
Hey, Alan, look at this.
血液的流动，表皮的瑕疵
amount of blood distending your vessels, imperfections in the skin--
表皮的瑕疵？
- Imperfections in the skin?
微细的瑕疵！
- Microscopic.
决不重复的瑕疵影响表皮
And never repeat, and vastly affect the outcome.
那是K什么？
- That's what?
不可测的
- Unpredictability.
对！
Right.
看见没有？ 你看见没有？我又说对了
There. Look at this. See? I'm right again. Nobody could've predicted that Dr. Grant...
没人料到葛博士 忽然跳下行进的车辆
would suddenly jump out of a moving vehicle.
亚伦！
Alan
还有一个例子
There's another example.
现在我独处K自言自语
See? Here I am now by myself, talking to myself.
那是混乱的原理
That's chaos theory.
停止这程式！停止！
Stop the program.
我说过多少遍车门要装锁
I've told you how many times... we needed locking mechanisms on the vehicle doors.
园车停止
Stopping park vehicles and rebooting program. We're on. Will notify for resume.
我说过贝克写书
Like I was saying, there's this other book by a guy named Bakker...
他说恐龙类死于K
and he says the dinosaurs died...
亚伦，我们上哪去？ 你看见什么了？
- of a bunch of diseases. - Where are we going? You see something?
有别人认为 我们不该来此地
Is there anybody else who thinks we shouldn't be out here?
他的书比你的书厚多了 有这么厚！
And his book was a lot fatter than yours was.
亲爱的，你的书尽是插图
- Really? - Yours was fully illustrated, honey.
你要紧吗？
- Hey. - You okay?
你看这个，等一下！
Hey, look at this. Hey, watch.
看呀！快看这个！
Hey, come on! Watch this!
大家留在这里！
Everybody stay here.
丁姆，丁姆！
Tim.Tim.
好吗？
- Okay?
当然！
- Of course.
不要怕！
Don't be scared. It's okay.
不要紧！马尔杜，帮我麻醉她
Muldoon tranquilized her for me.
她生病了
She's sick.
我的天！
Oh, my God.
宝贝儿
Hey, baby.
天啊！
Oh, my God.
喂！宝贝！
Hey, baby girl.
你看！
You look
天啊！我从小就喜欢三犄龙 她是最美丽的东西
She was my favorite when I was a kid. Now I see her, she's the most beautiful thing I ever saw.
不要紧！
It's okay.
小水泡，有意思！
Microvesicles. That's interesting.
谢谢，她是什么征状
Thanks. What are her symptoms?
失衡，无方向感呼吸急促
Imbalance, disorientation, labored breathing.
是！
- Right.
这情形似乎已有六周左右
- Seems to happen about every six weeks.
六周！
Six weeks.
瞳孔放大！
These are dilated.
-是吗？ -你看
- They are? - Take a look.
-不要紧！ -奇怪！
- It's okay. - I'll be damned.
不要紧！ 那是药理效应，来自植物
That's pharmacological... from local plant life.
这是西印度群岛丁香吗？
Is this West Indian Lilac?
是的，它有毒 动物并不吃它
Yes. We know they're toxic, but the animals don't eat them.
你确定吗？
- You sure?
非常肯定！
- Pretty sure.
只有一个方法可以肯定
There's only one way to be positive.
我要看恐龙的粪便
I'd have to see the dinosaur's droppings.
恐龙粪便？粪便？
Dino-- Droppings?
是，是，我听到了
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah, I got that.
暴风中心 没有消散或是转向
That storm center hasn't dissipated or changed course.
恐怕我们得缩短游程了
We're gonna have to cut the tour short, I'm afraid.
明天再继续未完的游程
Pick it up again tomorrow where we left off.
一定要缩短吗？
- Are you sure we have to?
-这不值得冒险，约翰！ -这个K
- It's not worth taking the chance.
风速持续四十五海里
- Sustained winds, 45 knots.
他们回车上时告诉他们
- Tell them when they get in the car.
各位女士先生
Ladies and gentlemen,
往码头的最后班车 五分钟后开
the last shuttle leaving for the dock...leaves in approximately five minutes.
放下手边的事马上离开
Drop what you're doing and leave now.
该死！
Damn!
这泡屎好大！
That is one big pile of shit.
说得对！
You're right. There's no trace of lilac berries.
没有丁香莓，这就奇怪了
It's so odd, though.
原来她每六周 中一次栋树果毒K
All right. So she's suffering from melia toxicity... every six weeks.
让我想想
Let's see.
老鼠...纳达合金...
Rats. Nada.
她K意志坚韧
She's tenacious.
超出你的想像
You have no idea.
记得吃东西前要洗手
You will remember to wash your hands before you eat anything?
“执行吗？”
各位博士，拜托！
Doctors, if you please,
我一定要大家走！
I have to insist that we get moving.
我想跟哈丁博士 把三犄龙照料好K
If it's okay, I'd like to stay with Dr. Harding and finish up with the trike.
好，我有汽油吉普车
Sure. I'm in a gas-powered Jeep.
我上船之前 送她到游客中心
I can drop her at the visitors' center before I make the boat.
好极了！ 如果要续游我会赶上
Great. Then I'll catch up with you.
你确定？
- You sure?
是呀，我要陪三犄龙
- I wanna stay with her a bit longer.
那好吧！
- Okay, then. - Okay.
快走！
Now!
我没办法！
There's nothing I can do.
船长要我们走就得走
The captain says we gotta go, we gotta go!
不行呀，你得给我时间！
Give me the time. I did a test run on this thing. It took me 20 minutes.
关机要20分钟 最快也要18分
最少也要给我15分钟 给我15分钟
I could maybe push it to 1 8, but you gotta give me at least 1 5 minutes.
不保证
No promises!
游客车辆正在回车库
Visitor vehicles are returning to the garage.
第一趟就出那么多事
So much for our first tour.
两条龙没出场 一条龙病倒
Two no-shows and...one sick triceratops.
不幸中的大幸 也可能更糟
It could've been worse,John. A lot worse.
有谁要喝汽水什么的？
Anybody want a soda?
我去贩卖机 顺便帮谁带东西
I'm going to the machine. I thought, maybe I'd get somebody something.
我都是吃甜食，想换咸的K 也许有人想K
I've had only sweets, and I'm gonna get something salty. I thought maybe somebody would--
我已经更正电话线路
Oh, I finished debugging the phones.
你知道我正要K我做好了
I was gonna-- So I did.
你叫我做的，我更正
You told me to, so I debugged the phones.
我想应该告诉你K 那系统处理要花18到20分钟
I should tell you the system is gonna be compiling...
有些小系统会时有时无
for 1 8 to 20 minutes.
别担心，小事情！
Some of the minor systems might go on or off, but it's nothing to worry about. It's a simple thing.
“改全岛监控划面” “是否执行？”
“码表”
“计时”
你有小孩吗？
You got any kids?
我？ 有，有三个，我喜欢小孩
Oh, hell, yeah, three. I love kids.
任何事都可能发生
Anything at all can and does happen.
所以老婆也是一样
Same with wives, for that matter.
你结婚了吗？
- You married?
偶而！
- Occasionally.
我一直在找未来的离婚对象
Yeah, I'm always on the lookout for a future ex-Mrs. Malcolm.
是呀！
Yeah
五、四、三K
Five, four...
二、一！
three, two, one.
“消毒气锁”
奇怪
That's odd.
什么？
What?
门户安全系统都关闭了
Door security systems shutting down.
丹尼斯不是说 有些系统会故障
Well, Nedry said a few systems would go off-line, didn't he?
“迅猛龙”
“暴龙”
“剑龙”
“胚胎冷藏，禁区”
对了，塞博士她K
By the way, Dr. Sattler...
她还是单身？ 她已经是死会了吧！ 要追她好像是不可能吧！
she's not, like, available, is she?
为什么？
Why?
对不起，你们俩K
Yeah, I'm sorry. You two are--
是呀！
Yeah.
我碰了什么？
Hey, what'd I touch?
你什么也没碰 我们停止了！
You didn't touch anything. We stopped.
“努布拉岛”
搞什么鬼？
Whoa, whoa. What the hell?
现在怎么办？
- What now?
网墙的电力都断了
- Fences are failing all over the park.
丹尼斯，检查贩卖机
Find Nedry! Check the vending machines.
“手控不受理，开启”
看看这张桌子，一塌糊涂！
Look at this work station. What a complete slob.
猛禽区的网墙也断电了吧
The raptor fences aren't out, are they?
没有断，还有通电！
No, no. They're still on.
他为什么把其他的关掉？
Why the hell would he turn the other ones off?
“危险，高压电”
“危险，通电网墙”
“东码头”
存取主程式！
Access main program.
“存取安全，不准” 存取主程式安全网
Access main security.
存取主程式！
Access main program grid.
“不准存取，你没念开门咒”
你没念开门咒
Uh, uh, uh. You didn't say the magic word.
拜托！可恶 这电脑口令真可恨
Please! Goddamn it! I hate this hacker crap!
打电话到剑桥 找丹尼斯的手下
Call Nedry's people in Cambridge.
电话也断了
Phones are out too.
车辆停在那里？
Where did the vehicles stop?
他们的无线电也断了
Their radio's out too.
金拿罗说别乱跑！
Gennaro said to stay put.
小孩都好吗？
- Kids okay?
我没问 他们怎么会不好？
- I didn't ask. Why wouldn't they be?
小孩们会怕
- Kids get scared.
怕什么？电力打嗝而已！
- What's to be scared about?
我没说我怕
I didn't say I was scared.
-我也没说你怕 -我知道！
- I didn't say you were scared. - I know.
喂，你从那找到那些？
- Hey, where did you find those?
从我坐位下的箱子里
- In a box under my seat.
-重不重？ -重呀！
- Are they heavy? - Yeah.
那就是贵重物，放回去！
Then they're expensive. Put 'em back.
不要吓我！
Don't scare me.
好酷，夜视镜！
Oh, cool. Night vision.
你感觉到了吗？
Do you feel that?
也许是电力要恢复
Maybe it's the power tryin' to come back on.
那是什么？
What is that?
那只羊呢？
Where's the goat?
“危险，一万伏特”
天呀！
Oh,Jesus!
我的天！
他丢下我们，他跑了
He left us. He left us.
他想上那儿去？
Where does he think he's going?
要拉的时候憋也憋不住
When you gotta go, you gotta go.
葛博士！
Dr. Grant?
我真恨我每次都说中
Boy, do I hate being right all the time.
保持绝对静止
Keep absolutely still.
它只看得见活动之物
Its vision is based on movement.
关灯，关灯！
Turn the light off. Turn the light off.
关灯！
Turn the light off!
关掉！快点关！
- Turn it off!
我很抱歉！
- I'm sorry!
怎么会开着 你为什么要开灯呢？
I'm sorry!
不
No!
在这里
Hey!
天
Oh, God.
这里！
Hey!Hey!Hey!
伊恩，不要动！
Ian, freeze!
去救孩子们！
Get the kids!
把火焰丢掉
Get rid of the flare!
去救孩子们！
- Get the kids!
把火焰丢掉
- Get rid of the flare!
万福马利亚K满被圣宠者
Hail Mary, full of grace. The Lord be with me--
不！不！
No
葛博士！
- Dr. Grant!
你能走吗？
- Okay, Lex, I got ya.
我卡住了 座椅夹住我的脚
I'm stuck! The seat's got my feet!
丁姆，我再来救你
I'll get you next. You're okay.
你没事！走，走呀！ 好了！丁姆，丁姆？
You're all right. Tim! Tim?
不要动！
Don't move.
我们不动他就看不见
He can't see us if we don't move.
走这边！快！当心！
This way-- Wait, wait, wait!
丁姆！丁姆！
Tim,Tin
天啊，抓紧
God ,hold on
莉丝！你勒死我了！
Lex! Lex! You're chokin' me!
抓住电线！
Grab the wire!
抓住电线，抓住
“关键检查空间负零”
'' Keycheck space minus O, keychecks off, safety space minus O.''
“关键检查关闭” “安全空间负零”
他把安全系统关掉了
He's turned safety systems off.
他不要任何人看见 他要做的事
Doesn't want anybody to see what he's doing.
现在看下一项输入 这很棘手
Now, look at this next entry. It's the kicker.
“白兔目标”
''White rabbit object.''
无论如何它都做了
It did it all.
关键检查关掉了 电脑没存档
With the keychecks off, the computer didn't file the keystrokes.
所以要找他们 必须一一清查电脑线码
Only way to find them is to go through the computer's lines of code one by one.
有多少线码？
- How many lines of code are there?
约有两百万条
- About two million.
-两百万？ -是呀！
- Two million? - Yeah.
劳勃！也许你会做好事
Robert, I wonder if perhaps you would be good enough...
开吉普车去接我的孙儿们
to take a gas jeep... and bring back my grandchildren.
好！
Sure.
我跟他去！
I'm going with him.
约翰！
John
没有丹尼斯 公园无法恢复正常
I can't getJurassic Park back on-line without Dennis Nedry.
现在我应该到那边了
Should have been there by now.
不好！
No damn good.
可恶！
Oh, damn!
该死！
There's the road!
“东码头”
把这笨玩艺绞离那东西
Winch this sucker off the thing
然后绑在那个东西上
and then I tie it to that thing and then I...
我再把这东西拉下来 然后再拉上去
pull down this thing here and I--
我的眼镜！
My glasses!
我买不起眼镜了
I can afford more glasses.
我的天！
Oh, geez!
该做的事你一定做得到
You got time, you got time. You can do it!
你做得到，加油！
You can do it. Come on, Dennis!
喂
Hello?
对！对！那很好！ 必须走了
Yeah, yeah, that's nice. Gotta go.
一切都会好的！
that's nice.
好孩子，乖孩子！
Nice boy. Nice boy!
恐龙乖！
Nice dinosaur.
我以为你是那些大恐龙
I thought you were one of your big brothers. You're not so bad.
你不错嘛！ 你要什么？
What do you want?
要什么？要一点食物吗？
You want food? Look at me.
你看我，我刚从山坡滚下来 全身湿淋淋，我没带食物
I just fell down a hill. I'm soakin' wet. I don't have any food!
我没带食物，什么也没带 去吧！
I have no food on me. I have nothing on me.
等一下！ 要玩抛接吗？玩抛接？
Play fetch? Play fetch?
你看，棍子
Look, see? See stick?
对！对！看着棍子！
See stick? Yeah, look, stick.
看！棍子！ 棍子！笨呀！
Look, stick! Stick, stupid!
去捡棍子，小子 看这棍子，对
Fetch the stick, boy!
你喜欢这棍子吗？去捡呀！
You like the stick?
难怪你会绝种
No wonder you're extinct.
等一下我开车把你轧扁
I'm gonna run you over when I come back down.
丁姆！
Tim
莉丝！别哭
Now, Lex,
别哭，听着
listen, listen to me.
莉丝，我在这里！
I'm right here.
我会照顾你 但是我得先救你弟弟
I'm gonna look after you, but I have to go help your brother.
我要你在此等我
So I want you to stay right here and wait for me!
他丢下我们 他丢下我们！
He left us. He left us!
我不会这样做
But that's not what I'm gonna do.
懂吗？
Okay?
留在这里！
Stay here.
丁姆！
Tim
听到没有？我上来了
You hear me? I'm coming up.
我厌恶爬树！ 我恨树，太高了！
I hate climbing. I hate trees. Way too high.
该死的大树
Goddamn tree.
喂，丁姆
Tim Tim
丁姆？
Tim
丁姆
你要紧吗？
You okay? You okay?
我呕吐了！
I threw up.
那不要紧！
Oh, that's okay.
手伸过来
Just give me your hand.
丁姆，我不会跟人家说 你吐了
I won't tell anyone you threw up.
只管伸手过来
Just give me your hand.
好！好了！我们走！
Ok,let't go
来，我抓住你了！
Here, I gotcha.
快，我们走！
Come on. That's good. Over the wheel.
慢点
- Don't pull me too hard. - No hurry.
-站在门上 -好了，我抓紧了
Stand on the door. Hang onto me. Okay, I got you.
好，不错吧，丁姆？
- That's not too bad, right?
是不错！
- Yes, it is.
就像是从树屋里出来 你爸帮你盖过树屋吗？
Just like coming out of a tree house. Did your dad ever build you one?
-没有！ -我爸也没有！
- No! - Yeah, me too.
爬树的要领 是决不要往下看
- Thing about climbing, never look down! -
但是这不可能 我怎么下去？这有五十英尺高K
This is impossible.-How am I gonna do this? It's about 50--
我会帮助你好吗？
-I'm gonna help you--
不，丁姆，快！
Oh, no. Tim, go!
快K丁姆，快！
Go, go, go!
小心！丁姆！
Faster!
丁姆，跳！
Jump!
丁姆，快！
Go!
我们又回到车里了
Well, we're back in the car again.
至少你已离开那棵树了
Well, at least you're out of the tree.
其他的车子呢？ 其他的车子呢？
Where's the other car?
亚伦！
Alan
葛博士！
Dr. Grant?
亚伦！
Alan
葛兰！
Dr. Grant?
我认为那是金拿罗
I think this was Gennaro.
我同意
I think this was too.
它大概是在我们前面
- I think it's ahead of us. - It could be anywhere.
它可能在任何地方 网墙倒了，它可以任意乱跑
With the fences down, it can wander in and out any paddock it likes.
绑止血带
He put a tourniquet on.
伊恩！
Ian
提醒我谢约翰 安排的可爱周末
Remind me to thankJohn for a lovely weekend.
我们可以冒险移动他吗？
Can we chance moving him?
拜托！冒个险！
Please chance it.
爱莉，快走！
Ellie, come on!
等一下！
Wait.
另一辆车！
The other car!
葛博士？
Dr. Grant?
天啊，亚伦！
God ,Alan
他们不在这里
They're not here.
有谁听到吗？
Anybody hear that?
惊天动地的脚步声
It's an impact tremor is what it is.
我这里拉警报了
I'm fairly alarmed here.
快点！快！快！ 我们得离开这里，必须离开！
Come on. We gotta get outta here.
现在！马上离开！
Now, now! Right now!
我们走，离开这里！
Go, go, go! Let's go!
马上走！
Start the engine!
走快一点
Must go faster.
-它追上来了 -它来了，它来了！
- Here it comes!  - Shit! Shit!
-踩油门，换五档！ -换五档，踩油门！
- Here it comes! Fifth gear! - Shit! Shit!
不要坐在手排挡上
Get off the stick! Bloody move!
当心
- Look out!
趴下
- Down!
游程中有这种场面吗？
Think they'll have that on the tour?
你有没有在听？
Are you hearing this?
丁姆，快！快点！
Come on, Tim. Come on, hurry up.
我们上这棵树，快！
Let's get up this tree.
丁姆，来呀！不要紧！ 听话！试爬爬看！
Come on. It's okay. Try up here.
我会尝试！
I don't want to.
好，爬上去！
Oh, man.
我恨死树了！
- I hate trees.
我不厌恶树！
- They don't bother me.
是吗？ 刚才的树你没爬过
Oh, yeah, well, you weren't in the last one.
喂，你看那雷龙 我是说K腕龙
Hey, those are brontosauruses. I mean, brachiosaurs.
他们在唱歌
They're singing.
不要让那怪兽过来
- Don't let the monsters come over here!
莉丝，他们不是怪兽 他们是动物
- They're not monsters, Lex. They're just animals.
这些是草食动物
These are herbivores.
那表示他们吃素 对你，他们会开晕
That means they only eat vegetables, but for you they'd make an exception.
好吧，我恨其他类的K
Oh, I hate the other kind.
其他类的 只是做他们该做的
The other kind just do what they do.
是什么？
What's that?
如果你和爱莉不挖恐龙骨头了 以后要做什么？
What will you and Ellie do if you don't have to pick up dinosaur bones anymore?
我想我们只好 “进化”一番了
I don't know. I guess we'll just have to evolve too.
瞎恐龙你怎么称呼？
What do you call a blind dinosaur?
不知道，你怎么称呼它？
他看得见我们吗？
Do-you-think-he-saurus.
恐龙的导盲犬怎么称呼？
What about a blind dinosaur's dog?
你问倒我了
You got me.
他看得见雷克斯吗？
A do-you-think-he-saurus' Rex.
亚伦？
Alan
什么事？
What?
我们睡着时 恐龙回来怎么办？
What if the dinosaurs come back while we're asleep?
我会醒着
Well, I'll stay awake.
通宵不睡？
All night?
通宵！
All night.
都融掉了
They were all melting.
马康姆暂时没事 我帮他打了吗啡针
Malcolm's okay for now. I gave him a shot of morphine.
他们都没事
They'll be fine.
带孩子们穿越公园的任务 谁会比恐龙专家胜任？
Who better to get the children through Jurassic Park than a dinosaur expert?
我从苏格兰来时 我盖的东西什么最吸引人
You know the first... attraction I ever built when I came down from Scotland...
跳蚤杂技团
was a flea circus, Petticoat Lane.
真的很棒！
Really quite wonderful.
我有K小空中飞人还有K
We had a wee trapeze and... a merry-go--
转K旋转木马
A carousel.
还有秋千
And a seesaw.
当然都是马达带动
They all moved. Motorized,
但是人们会说他们看得见跳蚤
but people would say they could see the fleas.
“我看得见跳蚤K” “妈咪，你看见跳蚤没有？”
''Oh, I can see the fleas, Mummy. Can't you see the fleas?''
跳蚤扮小丑 走钢索，游行
Clown fleas and high-wire fleas and fleas on parade.
但是在这里
But with this place...
我要呈现的不是幻觉
I wanted to show them something that wasn't an illusion.
而是真实的好东西
Something that was real.
人们看得见摸得着的东西
Something that they could... see and touch.
而不是浪得虚名
An aim not devoid of merit.
但是你不能凭想像
But you can't think through this one.
约翰，你必须感触它
You have to feel it.
你说得对！完全正确！
You're right. You're absolutely right.
我雇用丹尼斯显然是错了
Hiring Nedry was an obvious mistake. We're overdependent on automation.
我明白 我们过份倚赖自动化
I can see that now.
下次一切都可以改正
Now, the next time, everything's correctable.
约翰！
Creation...
创造是至高的意愿
is an act of sheer will.
下次的创造将无瑕疵
Next time, it'll be flawless.
这仍然是跳蚤杂技团 仍是虚幻的！
It's still the flea circus. It's all an illusion.
当我们再度掌控时K
When we have control again--
你永远控制不了 那是虚幻的
You've never had control. That's the illusion!
我曾被这里的力量所感动
I was overwhelmed by the power of this place!
但是我也错了！
But I made a mistake too.
我对那种力量不够尊敬
I didn't have enough respect for that power
现在它消失了
and it's out now.
现在只有一件事重要 就是我们所爱的人
The only thing that matters now are the people we love.
亚伦、莉丝、丁姆
Alan and Lex and Tim.
约翰 他们在外面有性命之忧
John, they're out there where people are dying.
所以
So
很好吃！
It's good.
不惜工本！
Spared no expense.
走开！
- Go away!
不要紧！这是腕龙
- It's okay. It's a brachiosaur.
这是素食恐龙！莉丝！ 素食恐龙！
It's a veggie-saurus, Lex.
素食！
Veggie.
来！来！女孩！
Come on. Come on, girl.
来！对！来！
Come on. Come on, baby.
好，我不放手！
All right! I'm not letting go.
好像是着凉了
- Looks like it has a cold.
对，也许是！
- Yeah, maybe.
我可以摸吗？
- Can I touch it? - Sure.
可以 就当它是一头大母牛
Just think of it as kind of a big cow.
我喜欢母牛
I like cows.
来！女孩！上来！
Hey, come on, girl. Come on up here, girl.
来！上来！
Come on. Up here.
上帝保佑你！
God bless you!
太好了
Oh, great.
她不会尝试玩新游戏了
Now she'll never try anything new.
她会坐在房间里不出门 玩她的电脑
She'll just sit in her room and never come out and play on her computer.
我是电脑骇客
- I'm a hacker!
对呀，你是电脑痴
- That's what I said. You're a nerd.
我不是，我是电脑骇客
I am not a computer nerd. I prefer to be called a hacker.
我的天
Oh, God.
可知这是什么？
You know what this is?
这是恐龙蛋！
It's a dinosaur egg.
恐龙在繁殖
The dinosaurs are breeding.
可是我外公说 恐龙都是母的
But, my grandpa said all the dinosaurs were girls.
两栖去氧核糖酸
（DNA） Amphibian DNA.
那是什么？
What's that?
游览介绍影片上说K
Well, on the tour, the film said they used...
他们用青蛙的DNA 补基因的断层
frog DNA to fill in the gene sequence gaps.
他们改变恐龙遗传密码
They mutated the dinosaur genetic code...
混合青蛙的密码
and blended it with that of frogs.
有些西非青蛙 在单性别环境里
Now, some West African frogs have been known to spontaneously change sex...
会本能的改变性别
from male to female in a single-sex environment.
马康姆说得对
Malcolm was right.
你们看！
Look.
生命会找出路
Life found a way.
不要！那太疯狂！
No, no, no, that's crazy. You're out of your mind.
你疯了，他真的疯了！
He's absolutely out of his mind.
等一下 这究竟是什么意思？
Wait a minute. What exactly would this mean?
我们是预估无可避免的损失 这是唯一的选择
We're talking about a calculated risk, which is the only option left to us.
我们休想找到丹尼斯指挥法 他一点破绽都没有
We will never find the command that Nedry used. He's covered his tracks far too well.
显然他是永远不会回来了
I think it's obvious now that he's not coming back.
所以关闭整个系统才是K
So, shutting down the entire system--
你找别人，我可不干！
You can get somebody else, because I won't do it.
要消除他所做的一切 唯有关闭！
Shutting down the system... is the only way to wipe out everything that he did.
依我的了解
Now, as I understand it, all the systems will then come back...
整个系统会以原始模式恢复 对吗？
on their original start-up mode, correct?
理论上是的！ 但是我们从未整个关闭
Theoretically, yes. But we've never shut down the entire system before.
也许它不会恢复，永远不会！
- It may not come back on at all.
但是我们能恢复电话吗？
- Will we get the phones back?
在理论上是可以
Yes. Again, in theory.
离氨基酸怎么样？ 我们可以使它生效
What about the lysine contingency?
那是什么？
- We could put that into effect. - What's that?
这是绝对不行的！
That is absolutely out of the question.
离氨基酸是用来防止K 万一这些动物离开海岛散布别处
The lysine contingency is intended to prevent the spread of the animals... in case they ever get off the island.
吴博士插入一种基因 它在蛋白质新陈代谢中
Dr. Wu inserted a gene that creates a faulty
制造单一缺陷的酵素
enzyme in protein metabolism.
这些动物不能造 氨基酸离氨酸
The animals can't manufacture the amino acid lysine.
除非他们靠我们供应离氨酸 否则会昏迷而致死
Unless they're supplied with lysine by us, they slip into a coma and die.
有人性命垂危
People are dying.
请你关闭这系统好吗？
Will you please shut down the system?
坐稳了
Hold onto your butts.
“总开关”
“系统准备完毕”
不要紧，看见那个没有
It's okay. Look. See that?
开动了，成功了
It's on. It worked.
等一下，成功了是什么意思？ 一切都还没电
What do you mean, it worked? Everything's still off.
也许关闭时冲开了断电器
Maybe the shutdown tripped the circuit breakers.
我们只要再打开 恢复少数系统
All we have to do is turn them on, reboot a few systems--
电话，安全门，其他几样
telephones, security doors, half a dozen others,
但是成功了，系统预备好了
but it worked. - System's ready.
断电器在那里？
- Where are the breakers?
保养厂，在另一端
Maintenance shed, the other end of the compound.
三分钟内 我可以恢复全园电力
Three minutes, I can have power back on in the entire park.
为了安全起见 大家到地下避难室
Just to be safe, I want everybody in the emergency bunker...
等阿诺先生恢复全面运转
until Mr. Arnold returns and the whole system is running again.
我好累！
- I'm tired. I'm hot. - My legs hurt.
伙计们，向前走！
Just keep going, guys.
依地图看 游客中心约在那高地过去一英里
The visitors' center is just about a mile over that rise.
只管前进！
Just keep--
那是什么？
What is that?
丁姆，能告诉我 那些是什么吗？
Tim, can you tell me what they are?
是加K加拉K加里米玛斯
Gallimimus.
那是肉食性K肉食恐龙吗？
Are those meat eating? '' Meat-asaurusses''?
你们看，队形方向改变
Look at the wheeling. Uniform direction changes...
就像是鸟群，躲避猎食者
just like a flock of birds evading a predator.
他们向这边过来了
They're flocking this way.
我现在就想走
- I wanna go now.
看它的吃相
-Just look how it eats.
拜托！
Please.
你一定不会再小看鸟了
I bet you never look at birds the same way again.
-是的！ -现在走！
Yes. Go now.
好，低身跟我来！
Okay. Keep low and follow me.
看好多血
Look how much blood.
天啊，出差错了！
Oh, God. Something went wrong.
出事了
Something's happened.
出事了！
Something's wrong.
这只是延误，如此而已 大游乐园都有延误
This is just a delay, that's all it is. All major theme parks have delays.
一九五六年 狄斯耐乐园开幕时
When they opened Disneyland in 1 956,
没有一样灵
nothing worked.
可是海盗馆故障了 不会吃游客
But if Pirates of the Caribbean breaks down, the pirates don't eat tourists.
我等不下去了，出事了
I can't wait anymore.
我要去恢复电力
Something went wrong. I'm gonna go get the power back on.
你不能就这样跑到路上
You can't just stroll down the road, you know.
我们稍安毋躁 他才去了K
Don't let's be too hasty. He's only been gone--
我跟你去！
I'm going with you.
好！
Yeah
抱歉！
Sorry.
这不像开厨房灯那么容易
Now, this isn't going to be just like switching on the kitchen light...
但是我能按图指点你过去
but I think I can follow this and then talk you through it.
对呀！
Right.
但是应该是我去！
But it ought to be me really going.
为什么？
- Why?
我是K你是K
- Well, I'm-- And you're--
听着！
- Look.
快，我们走
- Come on. Let's go.
等我活着回来 再讨论性别问题
We can discuss sexism in survival situations when I get back.
你只要带我一步一步走 我用第二频道
You just take me through this step-by-step. I'm on channel two.
好！
Right.
天啦
Oh, God. Oh, God.
一定是关闭时 切断网墙的电流
The shutdown must have turned off all the fences.
天啊，这些东西跑出来了 该死！丹尼斯也知道那不好惹
Damn it, even Nedry knew better than to mess with the raptor fences.
快！走这边！
Come on, this way.
我看见厂棚了 快跑可以到
I can see the shed from here. We can make it if we run.
不行，过不去！
No. We can't.
为什么？
Why not?
因为我们已成猎物
Because we're being hunted.
天啊！
- Oh, God.
在正前方的树丛里
- In the bushes, straight ahead.
不要紧！
It's all right.
不要紧才怪！
Like hell it is.
跑步，奔向厂棚！
Run. Towards the shed.
我瞄准她了
I've got her.
走！现在！
Go! Now!
阿诺先生！
Mr. Arnold?
约翰，我进去了
John, I'm in.
很好！你前方有金属楼梯
Great. Now... ahead of you is a metal staircase.
下楼梯
Go down it.
好，下去了
Okay. Going down.
下去二，三十英尺 到一处T站，左转！
After 20 or 30 feet you come to a T-junction. Take a left.
你必须跟主电缆走，约翰
- Have her follow the main cable.
我看得懂图表
- I understand how to read a schematic.
“危险，一万伏特”
那大概是表示电源关了
I guess that means the power's off.
这并不好笑
- That's not funny.
好棒
- That was great.
也许我们可以K我们可以
Well, maybe, we could--
可恶，是死路！
Damn it. Dead end.
等一下！等一下！
Wait a minute, wait a minute.
前面应该有右转处
There should have been a right turn back there somewhere.
爱莉，看你的上方
Ellie, look above you.
应该有一大捆管线 朝同一方向
There should be a large bundle of cable and pipes heading in the same direction.
跟着它走！
Follow that.
好，跟着管线走！
Okay. Following the piping.
丁姆，打赌我已翻过那边 而你还没爬到顶
I bet I could climb over the top... and be on the other side before you could get to the top.
你输了给我什么？
- What would you give me?
给你尊敬
- Respect.
好了，这不是竞赛
Come on, guys, it's not a race.
我看见箱子了
I see the box.
写着“高压电”
It says ''high voltage.''
好，我们上！
Good. Here we go.
翻过去
Over the top.
丁姆，慢慢来
Take your time, Tim.
很好，加油
That's good. Come on.
找立足点
Find your footing. Find your footing.
爱莉，你不能徒手扳开关
Ellie, you can't throw the main switch by hand.
你必须将主把手充压
You've got to pump up the primer handle in order to get the charge.
它是巨大扁平的灰色东西
It's large, flat and gray.
好，我开始了
All right, here I go. Okay?
一、二、三、四
One, two... three, four.
充压
Okay. Charged.
在“接触位置”字样下 有园形的绿色钮
Under the words ''contact position''...
上有“按停”字样
there's a round, green button which says, ''push to close.''
“按停”好！
'' Push to close.'' Okay.
按它！
Push it.
现在，红色钮是开 各别的系统
Now, Ellie, the red buttons turn on the individual park systems.
把它们按开
Switch 'em on.
降落场！游客中心K
“周界网墙”
现在下来
- Get down now!
丁姆，你必须跳下来！
- You're gonna have to jump!
你疯了，我不跳！
You crazy? I'm not gonna jump.
丁姆，电力快恢复了 快跳！
- Do what Dr. Grant says!
好，我数到三
- Let go! I'll count to three!
一！二！三！
One, two, three!
控制室，游览！
Control room. Tour.
这很容易接！松手 我在这里
I'm coming up to get you. I've gotta get Tim.
好，我数到三
Okay. I'm gonna count to three.
一！
One...
“暴龙网墙”
二！
two--
丁姆，你要紧吗？
他没有气了！
He's not breathing.
哈先生，我们又开业了
Mr. Hammond, I think we're back in business!
天啦
Oh, my God!
该死！
Goddamn!
阿诺先生！
Oh, Mr. Arnold.
聪明的女孩！
Clever girl.
丁姆！
Tim
丁姆，不要！
Tim,no
好孩子！
Good boy. Good boy.
好孩子！丁姆
Good boy. Good boy, Tim.
三！
Three.
哈？
Hello?
好，我得找到其他人
Okay. I'm gonna have to find the others...
送你看医生
get you to a doctor.
莉丝，你照顾丁姆！
Lex, you look after Tim. Hey!
好！瞧你怒发冲冠！
Your hair is all sticking up.
丁姆，活烤生人
Big Tim, the human piece of toast.
我很快会回来，保证！
I'll be back soon. I promise.
爱莉！
Lex
快跑！
Run.
爱莉！
Lex
你上哪去了？ 你上哪去了？
Where are you? Where are you?
只有两只
It's just the two raptors, right?
你确定第三只 被关住了吗？
You sure the third one's contained?
是，除非他们会开门
Yes. Unless they figure out how to open doors.
丁姆，是什么龙？
Timmy, what is it?
迅猛龙
It's a velociraptor.
它在里面
It's inside.
跟我来！
Follow me.
它在里面
It's in there.
控制室！
Control room.
-我们可以求救吗？ -我们得先恢复系统
- We can call for help? - We gotta reboot the system first.
上门闩！
The door locks!
爱莉，上门闩
Ellie, boot up the door locks!
天
God!
快上门闩
Boot up the door locks!
爱莉，退后，去上门闩
Ellie, get back! Boot up the door locks!
你一个人挡不住它
You can't hold it by yourself!
这是门闩系统，我知道
It's a UNIX system. I know this.
这是全园的资料 能告诉你一切
It's all the files of the whole park. It tells you everything.
我要找出正确的资料
I gotta find the right file.
拿那把枪
Try to reach the gun!
除非我动才能拿到
I can't get it unless I move.
快，莉丝！
Lex
就这样
That's it.
这可能是正确的资料
This might be the right file.
这资料不对！
Wait. It's coming. This isn't the right file.
快点，莉丝！
Come on, Lex!
-你找到了 -是呀！
- You got it? - Yes!
“系统封闭”
你成功了!
You got it!
好呀！
Yes!
好呀！就是它！
Yes, this is it!
那些通了？
What works?
电话，安全系统 你说得出来的都通了！
Phones, security systems. You name it, we got it.
葛兰？
Dr. Grant
哈先生，电话通了
Mr. Hammond, the phones are working.
孩子们好吗？
- The children all right?
孩子们平安！
- The children are fine.
通知大陆派直升机来
Call the mainland. Tell 'em to send the damn helicopters.
快冲进来了！
Gonna come through the glass!
葛兰！
Dr. Grant
走！走！
Move! Quick! Tim, move!
丁姆，放手！走呀！
Tim, let go. Yeah.
哈先生，慎重考虑之后
Hold onto me!
我决定不替你背书
After careful consideration, I've decided not to endorse your park.
我也不玩了！
So have I.
不要紧！不要怕！
It's okay, it's okay.
来吧！来吧！
Come on.
导演：史蒂芬史匹柏
编剧：米高克里顿 大卫柯比
原著：米高克里顿
制片：凯瑟琳肯尼迪 吉拉R.莫伦
演员：山姆尼尔
萝拉邓
杰夫戈博
李察艾登布禄 饰“约翰哈蒙德”
谢谢观赏